<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_us"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_us" /><updated>2022-03-31T18:51:20+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">codercuy</title><author><name>Moises Gamio</name></author><entry><title type="html">Spring Boot and OAuth2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/spring-boot-oauth2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spring Boot and OAuth2" /><published>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/spring%20boot%20oauth2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/spring-boot-oauth2/"><![CDATA[<p>This tutorial will show how to integrate OAuth2 with Spring Security in a Spring Boot application.</p>

<p>The Spring Boot application I am going to use is based on my previous article: <a href="https://codersite.dev/documenting-rest-api-openapi3/">Documenting a SpringBoot REST API with OpenAPI 3</a></p>

<h3 id="oauth">OAuth</h3>

<p><a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc6749">OAuth</a> is an authorization framework many companies use to secure access to its protected resources. It performs this by using access tokens.</p>

<p>The token represents a delegated right of access on behalf of the resource owner.</p>

<h3 id="roles">Roles</h3>

<p>OAuth defines four roles</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Resource Owner – the user who grants access to a protected resource.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Resource Server – store user’s data and http services and respond to protected resource requests using access tokens.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Client – the application which require access to protected resources on behalf of the resource owner and with its authorization.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Authorization Server – responsible for authenticating user’s identity and gives an authorization token.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="authorization-grant">Authorization grant</h3>

<p>An authorization grant is a credential representing the resource owner’s authorization used by the client to obtain an access token.</p>

<p>OAuth defines four grant types.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Authorization Code, for web apps that are server-side apps</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Implicit, optimized for clients implemented in a browser using a scripting language such as JavaScript</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Resource Owner Password Credentials, used when there is a high degree of trust between the resource owner and the client</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Client Credentials, used when the client is requesting access to protected resources based on an authorization previously arranged with the authorization server.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>The  Client Credentials grant type is the most appropriate for server-to-server applications, such as typical B2B interactions.</p>]]></content><author><name>moises</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This tutorial will show how to integrate OAuth2 with Spring Security in a Spring Boot application.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/oauthRoles.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/oauthRoles.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/powerful-things-markdown-editor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor" /><published>2020-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/powerful-things-markdown-editor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/powerful-things-markdown-editor/"><![CDATA[<p>There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</p>

<p>If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!</p>

<p>As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.</p>

<h2 id="special-formatting">Special formatting</h2>

<p>As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:</p>

<ul>
  <li><del>strike through</del></li>
  <li>==highlight==</li>
  <li>*escaped characters*</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="writing-code-blocks">Writing code blocks</h2>

<p>There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, <code>like this</code>. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:</p>

<pre><code>.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
</code></pre>

<p>If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/3.jpg" alt="walking" /></p>

<h2 id="reference-lists">Reference lists</h2>

<p>The quick brown jumped over the lazy.</p>

<p>Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.</p>

<h2 id="full-html">Full HTML</h2>

<p>Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:</p>

<p><iframe style="width:100%;" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>]]></content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/4.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/4.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Understanding Object-Oriented Programming concepts</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/understanding-oop-concepts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understanding Object-Oriented Programming concepts" /><published>2019-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/understanding-oop-concepts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/understanding-oop-concepts/"><![CDATA[<p>Object-oriented concepts give you a solid foundation for making critical design decisions.</p>

<h3 id="class">Class</h3>

<p>A class is a template or prototype that describes what an object will be. It defines its attributes(data) and behavior(methods). We must design a class before creating an object.</p>

<h3 id="object">Object</h3>

<p>An object is an instance of a class. When we create an object, we create real-world entities such as auto, bicycles, or dogs with their own attributes and own behaviors.</p>

<p>In Java we instantiate an object via the <em>new</em> keyword. When you design a class follow the <a href="https://codersite.dev/solid-principles-the-definitive-guide/">Single Resposibility Principle (SRP)</a></p>

<h3 id="abstraction">Abstraction</h3>

<p>Abstraction allows an object telling to its users what an application does instead of how it does it. You can see the essential buttons in your TV remote control, but you don’t care what happens behind when you press one of these buttons. In Java, we create abstractions via Interfaces and Abstract classes.</p>

<h3 id="encapsulation-and-data-hiding">Encapsulation and Data Hiding</h3>

<p>Restricting access to specific attributes and methods is called <em>data hiding</em>. Objects should not manipulate the data of other objects.</p>

<p>Encapsulation is the action to combine the data and methods in the same entity. In this way, we control access to the data in the object.</p>

<h3 id="inheritance">Inheritance</h3>

<p>La herencia es un proceso en el que una clase hereda los atributos y métodos de otra clase.</p>

<p>Inheritance provides the ability to create new classes with new functionalities maintaining the functionalities inherited. In this way, it promotes code reusability.</p>

<p>In Java, we create inheritance between classes via the <em>extends</em> keyword.</p>

<h3 id="polymorphism">Polymorphism</h3>

<p>Polymorphism means many shapes and is coupled to inheritance. For example, a Shape class defines a <em>draw</em> method, but Square and Circle’s subclasses will implement it differently.</p>

<h3 id="advantanges-of-object-oriented-programming">Advantanges of object-oriented programming</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Your program focus on data, not on functions. You create a program using objects, not functions.</li>
  <li>You define methods to control the access to its data.</li>
  <li>Objects communicate through methods - messages</li>
  <li>Application adapts to new changes.</li>
  <li>Objects has unique responsibilities.</li>
  <li>You don’t define global data. Every object contains its data.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>moises</name></author><category term="oop" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Object-oriented concepts give you a solid foundation for making critical design decisions.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/oop.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/oop.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>