<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_us"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en_us" /><updated>2023-03-22T15:02:53+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">codercuy</title><author><name>Moises Gamio</name></author><entry><title type="html">Elasticsearch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/elasticsearch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Elasticsearch" /><published>2023-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/elasticsearch</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/elasticsearch/"><![CDATA[<p>Elasticsearch is a popular search and analytics engine that is designed to store, search, and analyze large volumes of data quickly and in real-time. It is built on top of the Apache Lucene library and provides a distributed, scalable, and highly available solution for handling big data.</p>

<p>Elasticsearch was first released in 2010 by Shay Banon, and it has since become one of the most widely used open-source search engines in the world. It is commonly used by enterprises and organizations of all sizes to power a wide range of applications, including e-commerce websites, social media platforms, and even government systems.</p>

<p>At its core, Elasticsearch is a document-oriented database that stores data in the form of JSON documents. This makes it very flexible and easy to use, as it allows users to store any type of data in a schema-less format. Elasticsearch also provides a powerful search API that allows users to query data in real-time using a wide range of search criteria.</p>

<p>One of the key benefits of Elasticsearch is its distributed architecture. It is designed to run on a cluster of machines, and data is automatically distributed across the cluster for improved scalability and fault tolerance. This makes it ideal for handling large volumes of data, as it can easily scale to accommodate increasing data volumes or processing demands.</p>

<p>Elasticsearch also includes a wide range of built-in features and tools for data analysis, such as aggregations, filtering, and sorting. These tools make it easy to extract valuable insights from large datasets and can help organizations make better business decisions.</p>

<p>Another key benefit of Elasticsearch is its ease of use. It has a simple REST API that makes it easy to interact with the search engine from any programming language or platform. It also has a large and active community of users and developers, which means that there is a wealth of documentation and resources available to help new users get started quickly.</p>

<p>Overall, Elasticsearch is a powerful and flexible search and analytics engine that is ideal for handling big data. Its distributed architecture, powerful search API, and built-in data analysis tools make it a popular choice for enterprises and organizations of all sizes. With its ease of use and strong community support, it is an excellent choice for any organization looking to leverage big data for improved business outcomes.</p>

<p><a href="https://codersite.dev/hot-warm-architecture-elasticsearch/" target="_blank">Hot-Warm Architecture in Elasticsearch</a></p>]]></content><author><name>codercuy</name></author><category term="distributed systems" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Elasticsearch is a popular search and analytics engine that is designed to store, search, and analyze large volumes of data quickly and in real-time. It is built on top of the Apache Lucene library and provides a distributed, scalable, and highly available solution for handling big data.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/elasticSearch.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/elasticSearch.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Basic fundamental concepts of Programming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/basic-fundamental-concepts-programming/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basic fundamental concepts of Programming" /><published>2023-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/basic-fundamental-concepts-programming</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/basic-fundamental-concepts-programming/"><![CDATA[<p>The basic fundamental concepts of programming include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Data types: Data types are the basic building blocks of programming. They are used to define the type of data that a variable can hold, such as integers, floats, strings, and booleans.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Variables: Variables are used to store and manipulate data in a program. They are typically defined with a name and a data type.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Operators: Operators are used to perform operations on data. Examples of operators include arithmetic operators (+, -, *, /), 
comparison operators (==, !=, &lt;, &gt;), and logical operators (&amp;&amp;, ||).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Control structures: Control structures are used to control the flow of a program. Examples of control structures include if-else statements, loops (for and while loops), and switch statements.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Functions: Functions are reusable blocks of code that perform a specific task. They are typically defined with a name, input parameters, and a return value.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Objects and classes: Objects and classes are used in object-oriented programming to model real-world objects and their behaviors. A class is a blueprint for creating objects, while an object is an instance of a class.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Input and output: Input and output are essential for any program. They are used to get input from users, read data from files, and output results to the screen or to a file.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Error handling: Error handling is the process of anticipating and dealing with errors that may occur during the execution of a program. This includes catching exceptions, logging errors, and providing feedback to users.</p>
  </li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>codercuy</name></author><category term="programming" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The basic fundamental concepts of programming include:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/programmingFundamentalConcepts.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/programmingFundamentalConcepts.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What are the Software Design Principles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/software-design-principles/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What are the Software Design Principles" /><published>2023-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/software-design-principles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/software-design-principles/"><![CDATA[<p>Software design principles are guidelines and best practices that help software developers create high-quality, maintainable, and efficient software. Here are some commonly recognized software design principles:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>SOLID: SOLID stands for Single Responsibility, Open-Closed, Liskov Substitution, Interface Segregation, and Dependency Inversion. These five principles help developers create software that is modular, extensible, and easy to maintain.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>DRY (Don’t Repeat Yourself): The DRY principle states that code should not be repeated unnecessarily. Instead, developers should use abstractions, modularization, and other techniques to reduce repetition and make code more maintainable.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>KISS (Keep It Simple, Stupid): The KISS principle suggests that developers should strive for simplicity and avoid unnecessary complexity. This makes code easier to understand, maintain, and debug.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>YAGNI (You Ain’t Gonna Need It): The YAGNI principle encourages developers to avoid writing code that may be needed in the future but is not necessary at present. This reduces complexity and saves time and effort.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Separation of Concerns: This principle suggests that different concerns, such as user interface, data storage, and business logic, should be separated and handled independently. This makes code more modular, easier to maintain, and less prone to errors.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Composition over Inheritance: This principle suggests that developers should prefer composition over inheritance when designing software. This makes code more flexible and extensible and reduces code duplication.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Law of Demeter (LoD): The Law of Demeter suggests that objects should only communicate with their immediate neighbors and not with objects further down the chain. This reduces coupling and makes code more maintainable.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Design Patterns: Design patterns are proven solutions to common software design problems. Developers can use design patterns to create software that is modular, flexible, and reusable.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>These principles are not exhaustive, and there may be other principles that are relevant to specific types of software. However, these principles provide a solid foundation for creating high-quality, maintainable, and efficient software.</p>]]></content><author><name>codercuy</name></author><category term="software design" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Software design principles are guidelines and best practices that help software developers create high-quality, maintainable, and efficient software. Here are some commonly recognized software design principles:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/softwareDesignPrinciples.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/softwareDesignPrinciples.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What are the Soft Skills in Software Development</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/soft-skills-software-development/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What are the Soft Skills in Software Development" /><published>2023-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/soft-skills-software-development</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/soft-skills-software-development/"><![CDATA[<p>Soft skills are the personal attributes that enable individuals to interact effectively and harmoniously with others. In software development, having strong soft skills is just as important as technical skills. Here are some examples of soft skills that are valuable in software development:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Communication: Good communication skills are essential for effective collaboration between developers, project managers, and other stakeholders. This includes the ability to communicate technical information clearly and concisely, as well as the ability to listen actively and ask questions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Problem-solving: In software development, problems are inevitable. A developer with strong problem-solving skills can quickly identify issues and develop effective solutions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Teamwork: Successful software development requires a collaborative effort. Team players can work effectively with others, understand their role within a team, and are willing to lend a hand when needed.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Adaptability: The ability to adapt to new technologies, processes, and challenges is crucial in software development, where change is a constant.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Time management: Meeting deadlines is crucial in software development. Strong time management skills enable developers to prioritize tasks effectively and deliver projects on time.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Attention to detail: Paying attention to details can help developers catch errors, bugs, and other issues before they become bigger problems.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Creativity: Creativity can help developers find innovative solutions to complex problems, and come up with new and better ways to approach development challenges.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>These are just a few examples of soft skills that can be valuable in software development. Having a strong combination of technical and soft skills can help developers excel in their careers and contribute to successful software projects.</p>]]></content><author><name>codercuy</name></author><category term="software design" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Soft skills are the personal attributes that enable individuals to interact effectively and harmoniously with others. In software development, having strong soft skills is just as important as technical skills. Here are some examples of soft skills that are valuable in software development:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/softSkills.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/softSkills.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Clean Architecture</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/clean-architecture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clean Architecture" /><published>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/clean-architecture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/clean-architecture/"><![CDATA[<p>Building upon the success of best-sellers The Clean Coder and Clean Code, legendary software craftsman Robert C. “Uncle Bob” Martin shows how to bring greater professionalism and discipline to application architecture and design.</p>

<p>As with his other books, Martin’s Clean Architecture doesn’t merely present multiple choices and options, and say “use your best judgment”: it tells you what choices to make, and why those choices are critical to your success. Martin offers direct, no-nonsense answers to key architecture and design questions like:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>What are the best high level structures for different kinds of applications, including web, database, thick-client, console, and embedded apps?</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>What are the core principles of software architecture?</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>What is the role of the architect, and what is he/she really trying to achieve?</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>What are the core principles of software design?</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>How do designs and architectures go wrong, and what can you do about it?</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>What are the disciplines and practices of professional architects and designers?</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Clean Architecture is essential reading for every software architect, systems analyst, system designer, and software manager – and for any programmer who aspires to these roles or is impacted by their work.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Robert-C-Martin/dp/0134494164?crid=1LV51KASDAKVR&amp;keywords=sauberer+architektur&amp;qid=1665941680&amp;qu=eyJxc2MiOiIyLjA5IiwicXNhIjoiMC4wMCIsInFzcCI6IjAuMDAifQ%3D%3D&amp;sprefix=clean+archi%2Caps%2C118&amp;sr=8-1&amp;linkCode=li2&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;linkId=afda41dcae5ffd875fc17f89bd9933e8&amp;language=en_GB&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_il" target="_blank"><img border="0" src="//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=0134494164&amp;Format=_SL160_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=DE&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB" /></a><img src="https://ir-de.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB&amp;l=li2&amp;o=3&amp;a=0134494164" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
<a target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/3ez1CRL" class="btn btn-danger">Buy</a></p>]]></content><author><name>codercuy</name></author><category term="Coding Practices" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Building upon the success of best-sellers The Clean Coder and Clean Code, legendary software craftsman Robert C. “Uncle Bob” Martin shows how to bring greater professionalism and discipline to application architecture and design.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/cleanArchitecture.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/cleanArchitecture.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Pragmatic Programmer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/pragmatic-programmer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Pragmatic Programmer" /><published>2022-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/pragmatic-programmer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/pragmatic-programmer/"><![CDATA[<p>The Pragmatic Programmer is one of those rare tech books you’ll read, re-read, and read again over the years. Whether you’re new to the field or an experienced practitioner, you’ll come away with fresh insights each and every time.</p>

<p>Dave Thomas and Andy Hunt wrote the first edition of this influential book in 1999 to help their clients create better software and rediscover the joy of coding. These lessons have helped a generation of programmers examine the very essence of software development, independent of any particular language, framework, or methodology, and the Pragmatic philosophy has spawned hundreds of books, screencasts, and audio books, as well as thousands of careers and success stories.</p>

<p>Now, twenty years later, this new edition re-examines what it means to be a modern programmer. Topics range from personal responsibility and career development to architectural techniques for keeping your code flexible and easy to adapt and reuse. Read this book, and you’ll learn how to:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Fight software rot</li>
  <li>Learn continuously</li>
  <li>Avoid the trap of duplicating knowledge</li>
  <li>Write flexible, dynamic, and adaptable code</li>
  <li>Harness the power of basic tools</li>
  <li>Avoid programming by coincidence</li>
  <li>Learn real requirements</li>
  <li>Solve the underlying problems of concurrent code</li>
  <li>Guard against security vulnerabilities</li>
  <li>Build teams of Pragmatic Programmers</li>
  <li>Take responsibility for your work and career</li>
  <li>Test ruthlessly and effectively, including property-based testing</li>
  <li>Implement the Pragmatic Starter Kit</li>
  <li>Delight your users</li>
</ul>

<p>Written as a series of self-contained sections and filled with classic and fresh anecdotes, thoughtful examples, and interesting analogies, The Pragmatic Programmer illustrates the best approaches and major pitfalls of many different aspects of software development. Whether you’re a new coder, an experienced programmer, or a manager responsible for software projects, use these lessons daily, and you’ll quickly see improvements in personal productivity, accuracy, and job satisfaction. You’ll learn skills and develop habits and attitudes that form the foundation for long-term success in your career.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/David-Thomas/dp/0135957052?crid=16HTZ8PAMZYIG&amp;keywords=The+Pragmatic+Programmer&amp;qid=1665091792&amp;qu=eyJxc2MiOiIxLjkzIiwicXNhIjoiMS4xNiIsInFzcCI6IjEuMDMifQ%3D%3D&amp;sprefix=the+pragmatic+programmer%2Caps%2C333&amp;sr=8-1&amp;linkCode=li2&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;linkId=2eadc0f2d2c5047aa701bd7cbe38fdfd&amp;language=en_GB&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_il" target="_blank"><img border="0" src="//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=0135957052&amp;Format=_SL160_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=DE&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB" /></a><img src="https://ir-de.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB&amp;l=li2&amp;o=3&amp;a=0135957052" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
<a target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/3EjKjyx" class="btn btn-danger">Buy</a></p>]]></content><author><name>codercuy</name></author><category term="Coding Practices" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Pragmatic Programmer is one of those rare tech books you’ll read, re-read, and read again over the years. Whether you’re new to the field or an experienced practitioner, you’ll come away with fresh insights each and every time.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/pragmaticProgrammer.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/pragmaticProgrammer.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Domain-Driven Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/domain-driven-design/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Domain-Driven Design" /><published>2022-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/domain-driven-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/domain-driven-design/"><![CDATA[<p>Domain-Driven Design (DDD) software modeling delivers powerful results in practice, not just in theory, which is why developers worldwide are rapidly moving to adopt it. Now, for the first time, there’s an accessible guide to the basics of DDD: What it is, what problems it solves, how it works, and how to quickly gain value from it.</p>

<p>It is interesting the topic of Ubiquitous Language where the author emphasizes the importance of a consensual vocabulary among all team members involved in the same project. As developers, we need to choose the proper names for our variables that reflect that  Ubiquitous Language.</p>

<p>Vernon guides you through each core DDD technique for building better software. You’ll learn how to segregate domain models using the powerful Bounded Contexts pattern, to develop a Ubiquitous Language within an explicitly bounded context, and to help domain experts and developers work together to create that language. Vernon shows how to use Subdomains to handle legacy systems and to integrate multiple Bounded Contexts to define both team relationships and technical mechanisms.</p>

<p>Coverage includes</p>

<ul>
  <li>What DDD can do for you and your organization–and why it’s so important</li>
  <li>The cornerstones of strategic design with DDD: Bounded Contexts and Ubiquitous Language</li>
  <li>Strategic design with Subdomains</li>
  <li>Context Mapping: helping teams work together and integrate software more strategically</li>
  <li>Tactical design with Aggregates and Domain Events</li>
  <li>Using project acceleration and management tools to establish and maintain team cadence</li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Vaughn-Vernon/dp/0134434420?crid=S07AFEAC0VED&amp;keywords=Dom%C3%A4nenangetriebenes+Design&amp;qid=1659201626&amp;sprefix=domain+driven+design%2Caps%2C256&amp;sr=8-4&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;linkId=2b280b174d4bea6336591427bffbc24a&amp;language=en_GB&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_il" target="_blank"><img border="0" src="//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=0134434420&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=DE&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB" /></a><img src="https://ir-de.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB&amp;l=li3&amp;o=3&amp;a=0134434420" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
<a target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/3vqmMXe" class="btn btn-danger">Buy</a></p>]]></content><author><name>codercuy</name></author><category term="Domain-Driven Design" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Domain-Driven Design (DDD) software modeling delivers powerful results in practice, not just in theory, which is why developers worldwide are rapidly moving to adopt it. Now, for the first time, there’s an accessible guide to the basics of DDD: What it is, what problems it solves, how it works, and how to quickly gain value from it.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/domainDrivenDesign.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/domainDrivenDesign.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/patterns-of-enterprise-application-architecture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture" /><published>2022-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/patterns-of-enterprise-application-architecture</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/patterns-of-enterprise-application-architecture/"><![CDATA[<p>The practice of enterprise application development has benefited from the emergence of many new enabling technologies. Multi-tiered object-oriented platforms, such as Java and .NET, have become commonplace. These new tools and technologies are capable of building powerful applications, but they are not easily implemented. Common failures in enterprise applications often occur because their developers do not understand the architectural lessons that experienced object developers have learned.</p>

<p>Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture is written in direct response to the stiff challenges that face enterprise application developers. The author, noted object-oriented designer Martin Fowler, noticed that despite changes in technology–from Smalltalk to CORBA to Java to .NET–the same basic design ideas can be adapted and applied to solve common problems. With the help of an expert group of contributors, Martin distills over forty recurring solutions into patterns. The result is an indispensable handbook of solutions that are applicable to any enterprise application platform.</p>

<p>Armed with this book, you will have the knowledge necessary to make important architectural decisions about building an enterprise application and the proven patterns for use when building them.</p>

<p>The topics covered include</p>

<p>· Dividing an enterprise application into layers</p>

<p>· The major approaches to organizing business logic</p>

<p>· An in-depth treatment of mapping between objects and relational databases</p>

<p>· Using Model-View-Controller to organize a Web presentation</p>

<p>· Handling concurrency for data that spans multiple transactions</p>

<p>· Designing distributed object interfaces</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Martin-Fowler/dp/0321127420?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=1658871855&amp;sr=8-2&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;linkId=0160cf7b22f52ad146404caf5b3e5476&amp;language=en_GB&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_il" target="_blank"><img border="0" src="//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=0321127420&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=DE&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB" /></a><img src="https://ir-de.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB&amp;l=li3&amp;o=3&amp;a=0321127420" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" />
<a target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/3PFbM0v" class="btn btn-danger">Buy</a></p>]]></content><author><name>codercuy</name></author><category term="Enterprise Architecture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The practice of enterprise application development has benefited from the emergence of many new enabling technologies. Multi-tiered object-oriented platforms, such as Java and .NET, have become commonplace. These new tools and technologies are capable of building powerful applications, but they are not easily implemented. Common failures in enterprise applications often occur because their developers do not understand the architectural lessons that experienced object developers have learned.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/patternsArchitecture.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/patternsArchitecture.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Robo Wunderkind Robot</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/robo-wunderkind-robot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Robo Wunderkind Robot" /><published>2022-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/robo-wunderkind-robot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/robo-wunderkind-robot/"><![CDATA[<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Programming means finding solutions to problems. While learning to code, children also learn to work independently and to solve tasks in a creative way. Educational robotics tools like Robo Wunderkind are ideal to engage children in programming through play, equipping them with a skill set that helps them to thrive in a modern world.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Your children can learn to program a robot efficiently. Thirty-eight components are included. The possibilities are endless.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Compatible with Lego with the LegoTM adaptors. Exploit the creativity</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>An app is included, it allows to control the robot in real-time with intuitive symbols.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Children can build any maze of obstacles and control the robot through the console panel. “If” “Else” statements come to the children’s minds. This way of logical reasoning is fundamental in programming languages.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The parts are robust and easy to manipulate. Children can prototype, design, and build their robots in less than 7 minutes. Different sounds and lights are included.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>It helps to develop children’s cognitive skills and engage them in learning about technology.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>In-app tutorials and open coding interface: from guided projects to creating code from scratch.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Robo-Wunderkind-Robot-children-aged/dp/B08GS374TQ?crid=63QCQGG5FFN0&amp;keywords=robo%2Bwunderkind&amp;qid=1656275963&amp;sprefix=robo%2Bw%2Caps%2C136&amp;sr=8-2&amp;th=1&amp;linkCode=li2&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;linkId=828cfb9d629e558fac8b1014a72299fb&amp;language=en_GB&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_il" target="_blank"><img border="0" src="//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B08GS374TQ&amp;Format=_SL160_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=DE&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB" /></a><img src="https://ir-de.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB&amp;l=li2&amp;o=3&amp;a=B08GS374TQ" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></p>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/3ursZSD" class="btn btn-danger">Buy</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>Available in German an English</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="/assets/images/wunderkindRobot2.jpg" alt="wunderkind robot" class="img-responsive" /></p>]]></content><author><name>codercuy</name></author><category term="Educational Toys" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Programming means finding solutions to problems. While learning to code, children also learn to work independently and to solve tasks in a creative way. Educational robotics tools like Robo Wunderkind are ideal to engage children in programming through play, equipping them with a skill set that helps them to thrive in a modern world.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/wunderkindRobot.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/wunderkindRobot.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Osmo - Little Genius Starter Kit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/osmo-little-genius/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Osmo - Little Genius Starter Kit" /><published>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/osmo-little-genius</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/osmo-little-genius/"><![CDATA[<p>This toy is MAGIC. Once you open the box, you never will see your children bored. They engage immediately with every game included.</p>

<p>The language by default is English, but you can configure it in german and Spanish. The little monster naturally communicates with your children; that is amazing. You can enjoy looking at your children interacting with a real friend.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wrKGZYzvnMU" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>The camera captures the drawings with good quality, and the animations are entertaining. They can choose different adventures.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Osmo-Creative-Educational-Problems-Included/dp/B07S6MNDX8?crid=1YKZNH9MY3OYE&amp;keywords=osmo%2Bmonster&amp;qid=1654424368&amp;sprefix=osmo%2Bmonster%2Caps%2C106&amp;sr=8-3&amp;th=1&amp;linkCode=li2&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;linkId=2faa4523173fc70bcc81d026250dc8a6&amp;language=en_GB&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_il" target="_blank"><img border="0" src="//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B07S6MNDX8&amp;Format=_SL160_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=DE&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB" /></a><img src="https://ir-de.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB&amp;l=li2&amp;o=3&amp;a=B07S6MNDX8" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></p>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/3NnTvn5" class="btn btn-danger">Buy</a></p>

<h2 id="learning-worlds-for-children-from-6-to-10-years">Learning Worlds for Children from 6 to 10 Years</h2>

<p>With these games, your child develops essential math skills, vocabulary, shapes recognition, spatial distribution, and strategies when solving interactive games—highly recommended!</p>

<p>The voice output and the games are available in German and English.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amazon.de/901-00041-Genius-Starter-German-version/dp/B08HN48NC4?crid=29Q1CHB1PV5KY&amp;keywords=osmo&amp;qid=1654427714&amp;sprefix=osmo%2Caps%2C98&amp;sr=8-1-spons&amp;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEyWkxOWVZXMFpUMUswJmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUExMDQ1OTAxMzdUVEhXVVFJSENMQyZlbmNyeXB0ZWRBZElkPUEwNjEwMzI1MUNaSU42UllWQU1GViZ3aWRnZXROYW1lPXNwX2F0ZiZhY3Rpb249Y2xpY2tSZWRpcmVjdCZkb05vdExvZ0NsaWNrPXRydWU&amp;th=1&amp;linkCode=li3&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;linkId=2f7ccfc67561ff7fbfd552f5660eeaa2&amp;language=en_GB&amp;ref_=as_li_ss_il" target="_blank"><img border="0" src="//ws-eu.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;ASIN=B08HN48NC4&amp;Format=_SL250_&amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;MarketPlace=DE&amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;WS=1&amp;tag=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB" /></a><img src="https://ir-de.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=mkgv89-21&amp;language=en_GB&amp;l=li3&amp;o=3&amp;a=B08HN48NC4" width="1" height="1" border="0" alt="" style="border:none !important; margin:0px !important;" /></p>

<p><a target="_blank" href="https://amzn.to/3mlW8tC" class="btn btn-danger">Buy</a></p>]]></content><author><name>codercuy</name></author><category term="Educational Toys" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This toy is MAGIC. Once you open the box, you never will see your children bored. They engage immediately with every game included.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/osmoLittleGenius.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/osmoLittleGenius.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>